[{
        "question": "Which of the following is not relevant to networking ?",
        "option1": "Low-end stand alone hubs",
        "option2": "Stackable hubs",
        "option3": "Mesh network",
        "option4": "Bus hubs",
        "answer": "Option: D"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of network architecture that was developed by IBM ?",
        "option1": "SNA",
        "option2": "DECNET",
        "option3": "XNS",
        "option4": "Novell",
        "answer": "Option: A"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organisation draws up standards for modems ?",
        "option1": "CCITT",
        "option2": "BELL",
        "option3": "AT&T",
        "option4": "Hayes",
        "answer": "Option: A"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a class of LAN ?",
        "option1": "Broad band",
        "option2": "CSMA/CD",
        "option3": "Token bus",
        "option4": "Token ring",
        "answer": "Option: A"
    },
    {
        "question": "Network operating system that does not support symmetric multiprocessing (SMP) is",
        "option1": "Banyan (VINES)",
        "option2": "Microsoft NT Advanced server",
        "option3": "SCO unix",
        "option4": "Novell network 3.X",
        "answer": "Option: D"
    },
    {
        "question": "The topology with highest reliability is",
        "option1": "bus topology",
        "option2": "star topology",
        "option3": "ring topology",
        "option4": "mesh topology",
        "answer": "Option: D"
    },
    {
        "question": "Baud means the",
        "option1": "number of bits transmitted per unit time",
        "option2": "number of bytes transmitted per unit time",
        "option3": "rate at which the signal changes",
        "option4": "None of these",
        "answer": "Option: C"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which topology requires a central controller or hub ?",
        "option1": "Mesh",
        "option2": "Star",
        "option3": "Bus",
        "option4": "Ring",
        "answer": "Option: B"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which topology requires a multi point connection?",
        "option1": "Mesh",
        "option2": "Star",
        "option3": "Bus",
        "option4": "Ring",
        "answer": "Option: C"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which topology, if there are n devices in a network, each device has n-1 ports for cables ?",
        "option1": "Mesh",
        "option2": "Star",
        "option3": "Bus",
        "option4": "Ring",
        "answer": "Option: A"
    },
    {
        "question": "A network that contains multiple hubs is most likely conigured in which topology ?",
        "option1": "Mesh",
        "option2": "Tree",
        "option3": "Bus",
        "option4": "Star",
        "answer": "Option: B"
    },
    {
        "question": "A packet-switching network",
        "option1": "is free",
        "option2": "can reduce the cost of using an information utility",
        "option3": "allows communications channel to be shared among more than one user",
        "option4": "Both (b) and (c)",
        "answer": "Option: D"
    },
    {
        "question": "IEEE Project 802 divides the data link layer into which upper sublayer and which lower sublayer ?",
        "option1": "LLC, MAC",
        "option2": "MAC, LLC",
        "option3": "PDU, HDLC",
        "option4": "HDLC, PDU",
        "answer": "Option: A"
    },
    {
        "question": "One important characteristics of the hub architecture of ARC - net is",
        "option1": "directionalized trasmission",
        "option2": "access control and addressing",
        "option3": "multiple virtual networks",
        "option4": "alternate routing",
        "answer": "Option: A"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following device is used with an X-25 network to provide service to asynchronous terminals ?",
        "option1": "Repeater",
        "option2": "Bridges",
        "option3": "Gateway",
        "option4": "Packet assembled",
        "answer": "Option: D"
    },
    {
        "question": "In time division switches, if each memory access takes 100 ns and one frame period is 125ms, then maximum number of lines that can be supported is",
        "option1": 625,
        "option2": 1250,
        "option3": 2300,
        "option4": 318,
        "answer": "Option: A"
    },
    {
        "question": "Frequency of failure and network recovery time after a failure are measures of what concept of a network ?",
        "option1": "Performance",
        "option2": "Reliability",
        "option3": "Security",
        "option4": "Feasibility",
        "answer": "Option: B"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a protocol specifies that address of the sender means the most recent sender and not the original source, what does this mean ?",
        "option1": "Syntax",
        "option2": "Semantics",
        "option3": "Timing",
        "option4": "None of these",
        "answer": "Option: B"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following two networks can use possible hubs ?",
        "option1": "Ethernet",
        "option2": "Arcnet",
        "option3": "Both (a) & (b)",
        "option4": "All of these",
        "answer": "Option: C"
    }
]